The island of Komodo in Indonesia.
印度尼西亚，科莫多岛
Remote and barren.
偏远而贫瘠
Few people live here.
极少有人居住
It's ruled by a giant reptile.
被一种巨型爬行动物统治着
It looks like a survivor from the age of the dinosaurs.
它看起来像是恐龙时代的幸存者
The Komodo dragon.
科莫多龙 （科莫多巨蜥）
9 feet long.
体长九英尺
A top predator.
顶级食肉动物
Only one thing can challenge a dragon's dominance.
只有一样东西能挑战它的统治地位
Another dragon.
另一条龙
In the breeding season, males are drawn into savage conflict.
在繁殖季节，公龙们陷入了野蛮的战斗
Huge claws and 60 serrated teeth can inflict terrible damage.
巨大的利爪和60颗锯齿状的牙，可以带来毁灭性的伤害
The Komodo dragon is the only reptile that still rules the land...
科莫多龙是目前统治陆地的唯一爬虫类
as the dinosaurs once did.
就像当初恐龙称霸陆地一样
It can dominate here because it has no competition.
它能统治这里，是因为没有竞争对手
But for the rest of the world's reptiles and amphibians,
但世界上其它地方的爬虫和两栖动物
survival is a much tougher struggle.
生存意味着艰苦的斗争
Like the dragon, reptiles and amphibians seem primitive,
如科莫多龙，爬虫和两栖动物看起来很原始
better suited to an earlier age.
更适应远古的时代
Yet they have a surprising repertoire of extraordinary strategies.
但它们仍旧有令人吃惊的生存技巧
And they still thrive in many parts of the planet.
以致能在地球的许多地方兴旺发达
This is the story of how they do so.
这是一个讲述它们如何做到的故事
South America, the remote jungle where Brazil and Venezuela meet.
南美洲，巴西与委内瑞拉交界处的原始丛林
Sheer-sided mountains rise up from the jungle.
陡峭的山峰绝壁从森林里隆起
Few places on Earth are wetter.
地球上没几个地方比这儿更潮湿
It's the home of some ancient and very peculiar amphibians.
这里是一些远古而又奇异的两栖动物的家
The waterfall toad is just an inch long, the size of a postage stamp.
瀑布蟾蜍，体长一英寸，一枚邮票大小
Its special gripping hands enable it to clamber safely, high in the tree tops.
特殊的手掌能让它安全地爬到树顶
But it's not alone up here.
但在高处并不孤单
Most frogs and toads avoid predators by hopping out of danger.
大多数的蟾蜍和蛙靠跳跃脱离危险
But this toad never evolved the ability to hop for more than an inch
但这种蟾蜍没能演化出哪怕跳出一英寸远的能力
and that's nowhere near enough.
而且那也远远不够啊
One way it gets eaten.
一条路是被吃掉
The other way is thin air.
另一条路是虚无的空气
Not much of a choice.
没多少选择
But this isn't suicide.
但这并非自杀
It's a deliberate strategy,
而是成熟的策略
and one that depends on the size and strength
依靠那奇特的手掌
of those extraordinary hands.
所具备的尺寸和力量
Free-falling like this is a very effective way of escaping.
这种自由落体是非常有效的逃命手段
However, another toad on this same mountain has elaborated this strategy.
然而，这座山里有另一种蟾蜍将这一战术演绎得更为精彩
It lives a mile above the forest, on this plateau,
它生活在与下面世界隔绝的
cut off from the world below.
高出森林一英里的高原上
This is a pebble toad.
这是卵石蟾蜍
It too is only an inch long.
也只有一英寸大小
These rocks may seem a paradise for a toad.
这些岩石对蟾蜍来说看起来就像天堂
It's even wetter than the forest below and there are no snakes.
这儿比下面的森林更加潮湿，而且没有蛇
But there is a hunter here.
但这里也有捕食者
A toad-eating tarantula.
食蟾蜘蛛
It ambushes its prey.
它伏击猎物
Like the waterfall toad, the pebble toad can't hop.
跟瀑布蟾蜍一样，卵石蟾蜍也不会跳
But it has a different defence.
但它有不同的防守
It tenses its muscles, becomes rigid and turns itself into a rubber ball.
它绷紧全身肌肉，将自己缩成一团，好似橡胶球
It's so tiny and weighs so little
由于体型小、体重轻
that bouncing doesn't hurt it at all.
这种撞击根本不会伤害到它
Bizarre innovations like these are one of the reasons why
像这样奇异的战术就是
amphibians and reptiles are still so successful.
爬虫和两栖类仍旧如此成功适应的原因
Some of them, however,
它们中的一些
have hardly changed for tens of millions of years.
几千万年以来几乎没变过
Brazil's Pantanal.
巴西的Pantanal.
Over 50,000 square miles of swamp.
超过5万平方英里的沼泽
In the dry season, the water is reduced to isolated pools
在旱季，水位降低后形成一些独立的小湖
and then they contain the greatest concentration of crocodiles on Earth.
它们容纳着地球上数量最大的鳄鱼群
These caiman crocodiles
凯门鳄
are trapped and fast running out of food.
很快就陷入了缺少食物的境地
It will be a long time before the rains return and the rivers rise
距离雨季和河水的到来很长一段时间
bringing with them the caiman's prey...fish.
随水而来的还有它们的猎物：鱼
Being cold blooded they can go without food for months
作为冷血动物，它们可以几个月不进食
and stay inactive except when they squabble.
除非吵架，它们尽量保持低调
At last, the rains return and rivers swell.
最终雨来了，河水泛滥
All reptiles are experts at saving energy.
所有鳄鱼都擅长节省力气
The caiman simply line up and wait for the fish to come to them.
凯门鳄只是并排着，等待鱼往它们嘴里钻
Reptiles and amphibians must warm their bodies
爬虫和两栖类在活动之前
before they can become active and until then
必须先让身体暖和起来
they are slow-moving and vulnerable.
否则行动迟缓，非常脆弱
The quickest way to gain heat is to bask in the sun,
获得热量的最快办法就是晒太阳
as this basilisk lizard from Central America is doing.
就像这只中美洲怪蜥
The trouble is that exposing yourself
问题是这样暴露自己
inevitably makes you easily seen.
难免会被发现
But a conspicuous perch over a river like this
但是像这样明目张胆地趴在河面上
seems to be making yourself unnecessarily prominent.
看起来可不太明智
This basilisk's greatest threat comes from the sky.
这只蜥蜴的威胁来自天空
Dark shapes overhead make it nervous.
空中的阴影让它恐慌
A hunting bird might expect it to flee to the trees.
猎食的鸟预料它也许会逃进树林里
In fact, it does the opposite.
但事实恰好相反
This skitter across the surface of the water earns it precious seconds
水上疾走只需短短数秒
and the nickname, Jesus Christ lizard.
因此得一名号：耶稣蜥蜴（能行走于水上）
It drives its feet down so hard and so fast
由于力量够强、步频够快
that it never sinks deeper than a few inches.
它在水面下沉往往不到几英寸
A human would need to run at 65mph to do this.
人要做到这样，必须跑出65英里的时速（104公里/时）
Reptiles are certainly expert at avoiding trouble
爬虫类显然都是逃跑专家
but they are also very good at finding a way to live in places
它们也非常擅长，在看起来不怎么适合它们
that don't seem to suit them at all.
的地方找到生存之道
They once included the largest animals that have ever walked the Earth...
它们包括，曾在地球上横行的最大的动物
the dinosaurs.
恐龙
And some living ones are a million times smaller than T Rex.
有些却比雷克斯猫(一种鬈毛家猫, 产于英国)小一百万倍
Smaller indeed, than some insects.
比一些昆虫还小
The Brazilian pygmy gecko could sit comfortably on a finger tip.
这种巴西小壁虎可以稳稳地坐在指尖上
It's so exceptionally small that no other reptiles compete with it.
没哪种爬虫比它还要小了
But it's so nimble
但是它相当敏捷
it can escape from the hunting monsters of the undergrowth.
能够逃脱灌木丛里的猎食者
It is so small that it has special problems with, for example, rain.
太小也会有特殊的麻烦，比如说：雨
It could drown in a drop
一滴雨就能淹掉它
but its skin is hydrophobic.
但它的皮肤是不沾水的
Rain cannot wet it.
雨淋湿不了它
A tumble into a puddle, you might think,
如果跌进水坑里
would risk death by drowning.
你可能会觉得它有溺死的危险
But the gecko is unsinkable.
但小壁虎压根儿就不会下沉
It's so light and its skin sowater-repellent
太轻，皮肤又非常油
that it canliterally stand on water.
它能够稳稳地趴在水上
Such miniaturisation is certainly very impressive
如此小的体型自然让人印象深刻
but the reptile body can be transformed even more dramatically.
但是爬虫的身体会发生更为戏剧性的变化
One of the most bizarre of allreptiles
在马达加斯加
hunts insects herein Madagascar.
最为奇特的爬虫正在捕食昆虫
The praying mantis has 360 degree vision
螳螂拥有360度的视野
but it hasn't seen the danger thatisnow approaching.
但还是没看到危险已经来临
A panther chameleon.
变色龙
Every part of its body
身体的每一部分
has become specialised for a life of stealth among the branches.
都演化得高度适应这种隐秘的丛林生活
Its toes have become grasping pincers.
脚趾如钳子般有力
Its eyes rotate so it can look in all directions.
两眼独立转动，所以能看到各个方向
Its skin can change colour for camouflage or to signal emotions.
皮肤能通过变色来伪装，或者表达情感
The chameleon body is concealed from both predator and prey,
变色龙能在天敌和猎物面前隐身
so it can launch a surprise attack.
因此能发起突袭
The tongue is a like a missile,
它的舌头就像制导导弹
aimed at its prey's head to neutralise its defences.
瞄准猎物直接摧毁其防线
Chameleons, in short, are so perfectly adapted
简言之，变色龙
to a life spent hunting in trees
完美适应了丛林捕猎生活
that it's hard to imagine how they could live anywhere else.
很难想像它们在其它地方该如何生存
The Namib Desert.
纳米布沙漠
There are no trees for hundreds of miles.
连绵数百英里没有树木
Yet these are,undoubtedly, chameleon foot prints.
但这些确实是蜥蜴的脚印
This female Namaqua chameleon is searching for a mate.
这只雌性蜥蜴正在寻找配偶
No part ofher body seems suited tosuch an environment.
看起来它身体的每一部分都不适应这里的环境
Her feet, that could give her such a good grip on twigs,
它的脚，能够帮助它紧紧抓住树枝
shouldsurely be useless on soft sand.
但在松软的沙地上似乎没什么用处
But she's able to spread them like snow shoes.
但它能摊开脚掌，就像滑雪板
She needs to get warm and active while the desert is still cool
沙漠还很凉，但它的身体需要尽快热起来以便活动
so she exploits the chameleon's versatile skin.
因此它独特的皮肤起发挥了作用
The side facing the sun goes dark to absorb the sun's heat,
朝阳的那一面颜色变深，以便吸收阳光的热量
while the other remains light
背光一面仍旧是浅色
and minimises the heat escaping from her body.
极少热量能从它的身体流失
She's hungry and food is scarce.
它很饥饿，食物稀少
But she's still not quick enough to grab these desert beetles.
但它动作还是不够快，抓不到这些甲虫
Her solution is simple.
它的策略很简单
She finds, at last, a little vegetation
找到一丛草
and waits for ashade-seeking beetle to come to her.
等待着寻找树荫乘凉的甲虫送上门来
On she goes, in her search for a mate.
然后，它继续上路寻找男友
At last, a wandering male.
最终，一位浪子出现了
But he may not treat her as she might wish.
但他也许并不会如她所愿地对她
The courtship of most chameleons is gentle.
大部分蜥蜴的求爱期都很短
But in this desert,
在这片沙漠里
a male meets a female so rarely he can't risk being rejected.
雌雄相遇机会难得，他不敢轻易拒绝
She marcheson, now carrying a new generation.
她继续前进，现在已经怀上了下一代
A six-month freeze,
六个月的冰冻
when temperatures may drop to minus 40 degrees centigrade,
气温会跌至零下40摄氏度
should surelymake things impossible for a reptile.
对爬虫来说绝无生存之可能
But here in Canada, beneath the thawing snow, something stirs.
但在加拿大，融雪下面，有东西蠢蠢欲动
A male red-sided garter snake.
一条雄性红色束带蛇
He survived the winter by hibernating underground
通过地下冬眠度过严寒
where the temperature never dropped below zero.
那里气温从没有低过零下
The weak sun persuades more males to emerge.
微弱的阳光让更多的雄蛇现身
They are cold and can't move fast, yet they are in an urgent race.
虽然身体还是冷的，移动缓慢，但它们仍然争先恐后
The first males to warm up will have a head start,
最先热身的的雄蛇将会在第一条雌蛇出现时
when the first females appear.
占得先机
Melt water provides the first drink they've had for six months.
融化的雪水是它们六个月来喝下的第一口
At last, a female has emerged.
最后，一条雌蛇出现了
The warmest males will inevitably be the first to react to her smell.
身体最热的雄性，将会对她的气味最先做出反应
She will only mate once, so competition between them is intense.
她只会交配一次，所以他们之间的竞争很紧张
This male has overslept.
这条蛇睡过头了
He will need hours to warm up.
还需要好几个小时来热身
At the moment he stands no chance of mating.
此时，他没有交配的机会
Most of the other males are ready to chase females but, curiously,
大部分的雄蛇准备好追求异性，但是，很奇怪
some leave the race and go to join the cold male.
有一些弃权了，奔向那条冰冷的雄性
They slide their warm bodies over him,
将自己暖和的身体滑过他冰冷的身体
just as they would if they were courting a female.
就如同他们正在和雌性亲热
More and more males crowd round him. Why?
越来越多的雄性朝他涌来，为何？
Their relative temperatures show what's going on.
它们的热成像图显示了所发生的故事
His cool body, showing as blue,
他冰冷的身体，呈蓝色
is quickly warming as it absorbs heat from the other males.
通过吸收周围雄性的热量，迅速热起来了
He's a trickster, he's fooled the others by giving off a scent
原来他是个骗子，通过散发出一种雌蛇的气味
just like a female's and they are trying to mate with him.
诱骗其他雄性来与他交配
He only needs a few minutes of this to steal enough heat from his rivals
他只需几分钟，就能从对手们那里骗来的足够热量
to catch up and join the chase.
完成热身，参与竞争
Every spring, tens of thousands of garter snakes
每个春天，上万条红色束带蛇
fight it out in this mating frenzy.
上演一场交配大战
It is, in numbers, the greatest gathering of reptiles in the world.
成了世界上数量最多的爬虫聚会
Getting a mate is just the first challenge a reptile faces
寻找配偶只是爬虫们繁育后代
whenit's ready to breed.
所遇到的第一个挑战
This collared iguana in Madagascar
这只马达加斯加鬣鳞蜥
will only lay one batch of eggs thisyear,
今年只会产一窝卵
so she needs somewhere safeto hide them.
所以需要一个安全的地方隐藏起来
Her eggs are much sought after by predators,
它的卵很受捕食者欢迎
they'reexcellent pre-packaged meals.
是包装精美的套餐
She appears to have the answer.
看来她有了办法
She covers all traces of where she buried them.
她擦掉了埋藏地点附近的所有足迹
It's a good strategy.
这是个不错的计策
But not good enough.
但还不够
Hog-nosed snakes have learned to keep watch on iguana nesting sites
猪鼻蛇学会了盯梢鬣鳞蜥的产卵地点
and to note the precise place where the eggs lie buried.
然后在埋藏地点做记号
She has been completely outwitted.
她被彻底的打败了
She can only stand by and watch as her precious eggs are eaten.
只能眼睁睁的看着宝贝们被吃掉
Next yearshe'll have to find a nesting site
下一年她必须找一个
without a hog-nosed snake.
没有猪鼻蛇的产卵地点
On the other side of the world, in the Sonoran Desert of Arizona,
在世界另一边，亚利桑那沙漠
a similar drama has a very different outcome.
相似的剧本却有不同的结局
A female horned lizard guards herburied eggs
一只雌性角蜥守护着埋下的蛋
and is keeping a lookout for anything
严防一切会对它们
that mightinterfere with them.
造成干扰的因素
A western patch-nosed snake.
一条西部斑鼻蛇
It is an egg-eater.
专门吃蛋
And she won't stand for it.
她不会容忍
The patch-nose is no match for this kind of aggression.
这条蛇还不是她的对手
Her eggs are safe, for now.
她的蛋蛋们暂时安全了
Another predator, a coachwhip snake.
另一猎食者，鞭蛇
And this species is a lizard eater.
这种蛇专吃蜥蜴
And she can tell the difference.
她知道实力差距
The snake is too fast for herto outrun it.
这种蛇很快，她来不急逃走
So she makesherself look larger and taller.
所以她把自己变得看起来更为高大
The snakeis wary of swallowing anything
鞭蛇不敢轻易吞下
thatlooks as big and as spiky as this.
像这个看起来又大、又多刺的东西
And now the lizard plays her trump card.
现在，蜥蜴亮出王牌
The snake isn't accustomed to prey that does this.
鞭蛇还不习惯于捕食这样的猎物
One very confused snake.
一条被搞懵了的蛇
Now she can return to guard duty,
现在她可以回去继续守卫
and several months later she's rewarded with her first baby.
几个月后，她便迎来了第一个宝贝
Looking after your eggs is an even greater challenge for reptiles
照看自己所下的蛋，对于离开陆地
thathave left land to live in the sea.
去到海洋生活的爬虫来说是个更大的挑战
The Pacific island of Niue is home to the world's entire population
太平洋上的纽埃岛是世界上
ofone particular type of sea krait.
一种特殊金环海蛇的家
This snake is superbly adapted to life underwater
这种蛇习惯了水下生活
except when it's time to breed.
除非到了繁殖季节
After a few minutes in a mating coil, the female is fertilised.
在几分钟的交配过后，雌蛇已经受精了
But now she has a problem.
现在，她面临一个问题
Reptile eggs can't survive underwater,
爬行动物的卵在水下无法存活
the developing young would drown.
发育中的后代会溺死
They have to be able to breathe air.
它们必须呼吸空气
She and her eggs are both vulnerable to predators,
如果返回陆地，她和她的宝贝蛋蛋们
if they return to land.
都容易受到天敌攻击
But she hasan extraordinary solution.
但她有特别的解决办法
She dives beneath the island.
她潜入岛下
To find the entrance to a long underwater tunnel.
找到一条长长的水下通道
At the far end is a cave with an air pocket.
通道尽头是一个有空气的洞穴
This is the dry land her eggs need.
这就是蛋蛋们需要的地方
There are no predators here.
这里没有天敌
The cavern is sealed by a roof above and the water below.
这个洞穴下面是水，上面封顶
She searches for a crevice where she can deposit her eggs.
她找到一个裂缝，将蛋产下
The eggs will be completely safe here
在这里，蛋蛋们绝对安全
and she can return to the open sea.
她也可以返回大海了
Six months later, a baby snake takes its first breath.
六个月后，小蛇会吸入第一口空气
Somehow, the young snakes must find their own way to water.
然而，小蛇们必须自己找到入水的路
Then down the tunnel and out to sea.
沿着通道，到达大海
A male giant bullfrog.
一只雄性大牛蛙
Reptiles and amphibians rarely care for their young after theyhatch
爬虫和两栖动物极少照顾已经孵化的幼仔
but this South African bruiser is an exception.
但这只南非的大块头是个例外
The males sort out their dominance through combat.
雄性们通过战斗划分领地
The strongest will mate with the most females.
强者能和大多数异性交配
You might not expect such anaggressive male
你可不会期待这么好斗的雄蛙
to bea caring father.
会是个细心的爸爸
Yet one male stays behind to watch over, not just his own,
但这只雄蛙留下来，看守不止自己的
but everyone else's offspring.
甚至包括别人的后代
The females laid their eggs in the shallows
雌蛙将卵产在
around the margins of the pool.
水池周围的浅水区
But the sun is intense
但太阳很烈
and the shallows have shrunk to a single pool.
浅滩缩成了一个小小的水坑
There's a real danger that the tadpoles will be stranded.
蝌蚪们有被困住的危险
The guardian male recognises the problem.
守护者意识到了这个
They will be dead within an hour unless he can do something to help.
除非它帮忙，一小时内它们就会死掉
There is only one thing he can do to save them.
要救它们，它只有一个办法
Dig a channelto themain pool.
挖一条通到大水池的水渠
They're safe.
它们安全了
Remarkable innovations have made amphibians and reptiles
引人入胜的新策略使得爬虫和两栖动物
amodern success story.
在现代成名
What is more, among their ranks is one reptile
更有甚者，它们中间有一种爬虫
that is stillan undisputed top land predator.
是毫无争议的陆地食肉动物之王
The Komodo dragon.
科莫多龙
They mostly hunt deer, which they ambush and easily overpower.
它们大多数能轻而易举地捕食鹿
But in hard times the dragons risk hunting something much bigger.
但在困难时期，科莫多龙会冒险捕食更大的动物
Water buffalo, an animal ten times their size.
水牛，比它们体型大十倍
Until now, adragon hunt has never been filmed.
直到现在，还没有拍到龙猎食水牛的镜头
It's the dry season.
旱季
A buffalo sleeps through the heat of the day
一头水牛在炎热里酣睡
in one of the last waterholes.
最后的几个水坑之一
Dragons lurk around the margins.
科莫多龙们埋伏在一旁
The buffalo seems to view them as just an irritation,
在水牛看来，这只会觉得不爽
not a danger.
而不会觉得危险
A serious mistake.
这是个严重的错误
The dragon is wary a jab or a kick could injure it fatally.
科莫多龙小心翼翼，被戳到或被踢到会造成重伤
The bites are just flesh wounds but other dragons are alert now.
这一咬只是皮肉之伤，但其它龙开始躁动起来
Like sharks, they're excited by blood.
就像鲨鱼，它们被鲜血刺激得很兴奋
The buffaloleaves with just a limp.
水牛跛着脚离开了
The dragons appear to have failed.
科莫多龙们看起来失败了
Yet they show a peculiar interest in the buffalo
但它们对水牛显示出极大的兴趣
and follow it wherever it goes.
无论它去哪里都跟着
As the days pass, the buffalo's wounds don't heal.
几天下来，水牛的伤口无法愈合
It starts to weaken.
它的身体开始虚弱
The dragons' hunting method begins to come clear.
科莫多龙的猎食方法开始明朗起来
A brand new discovery reveals that the dragon has venom, like a snake.
一份新的研究显示，科莫多龙能分泌毒液，如同毒蛇
The bite will eventually prove fatal
那一咬最终可以致命
but it's going to take several weeks.
但前后需要几周时间
The dragons, however, can afford to wait for a meal of this size.
科莫多龙，为了这一顿大餐，它们等得起
They simply stick close to their victim and conserve their energy.
它们只是简单的跟着猎物，保存体力
Thousands of years ago, dwarf elephants lived here.
数千年前，矮象（估计已灭绝）曾生活在这里
The dragons probably hunted them in exactly the same way.
科莫多龙可能就是用同样的方法，将它们猎食殆尽的
But the process is a long, drawn out one.
整个过程很漫长
Three weeks later and the buffalo is very weak.
三周后，水牛已经极度虚弱
The dragonssense that the end is near.
科莫多龙意识到，就要结束了
They must remain wary, the buffalo could still lash out.
它们仍需小心，水牛可能会猛力还击
Gradually they closein to try and finish it off.
慢慢地，它们试探着靠近，结果了它
The dragons'strategy is certainly merciless
科莫多龙的战术是残酷的
but it is the only way that they can get a meal like this
但像这样的大餐，只能用这一方法才能得到
and in hard timesthey need it if they're to survive.
在困难时期，想要生存，它们确实需要这样的大餐
The buffalo died in the night.
夜间，水牛死掉了
Tenbig dragons have gathered to feed.
十条巨龙聚在一起会餐
They strip the buffalo to the bone in just four hours.
四小时后，水牛只剩下一副骨架
This is the biggest venomous animal on the planet.
这是地球上最大的有毒动物
We don't need tales of Jurassic Park and Velociraptors
我们不必借助于侏罗纪公园的故事
to see a reptiledominated world.
来看爬虫怎样统治世界
It's all here.
这里就有
No-one has ever before followed the whole process
之前从没有人跟随拍摄过
of aKomodo dragon hunting a buffalo.
科莫多龙猎食水牛的全过程
So cameraman Kevin Flay and researcher Matt Swarbrick
所以摄影师Kevin Flay和研究员Matt Swarbrick
didn't know what to expect.
不知道会发生什么
They thought it would be a physicalchallenge
他们以为这只是对身体的考验
but they hadn't bargained for emotional turmoil as well.
没想到对他们的情感冲击更大
They reached Komodo after a four day journey.
经过四天跋涉，他们到达科莫多岛
Kevin, an expert at filming reptiles,
Kevin，一位专业摄影师
knows they're in dragon territory.
深知他们已经闯入了龙的地盘
Lookhow wide that is.
看看这些宽大的（脚印）
Look at that.Yes.
看看这个
Their only protection is these rangers, armed with sticks.
他们唯一的防护，是手持木棍的护林员
These big ones look really scary, actually.
体型较大的龙看起来确实很可怕
And not until you get, till they come really in close
直到它们靠近时，你更会体验到这一点
and when they're by the camera, then you tend to question your faith
它们出现在镜头里时，你会怀疑自己
in our friends with the sticks.
是否信得过那些拿树枝保护你的人
But this dragon isn't a big one.
但这条龙并不大
At five foot, this dragon is just over half grown.
五英尺长，才半大
The really big ones live in land,
真正的大家伙住在内陆
which is exactly where Kevin andMatt must go
Kevin和Matt正是要去那个地方
to find a place where dragons and buffalo might meet.
找一个水牛和龙会遭遇的地点
We could spend five weeks walking around all over the island
我们会花费五周时间走遍这个岛
just trying to find dragons randomly coming across buffalos
只为找到一个龙和水牛相遇的场景
but fortunately for us it is the dry season
幸运的是，现在是旱季
and there's only one decent waterhole left on the island
岛上只剩下一个水池
and both the dragons and the buffalo require water, obviously,
显然，科莫多龙和水牛都需要水
which brings them together.
这样它们就会碰头
Kevin decides to wait here,
Kevin打算在这儿等候
but aftera few days with no sign of dragons,
但几天下来没见着龙的影子
it looks like the wrong decision.
看起来这是个错误的决定
Oh, here comes a buffalo.
噢，来了一头水牛
You know this is about as, as exciting as the day gets.
你知道，这是这几天最兴奋的事情
Look.
看
See that.
看那个
Hello, mate.
你好啊
After almost a week something changes
差不多一周后，情况有变
and a couple of dragons appear.
几条龙出现了
Have we got a ranger here?
有护林员吗？
Guys, can we have a ranger?
伙计们，护林员呢？
Always know how dangerous a situation is,
我们都知道危险程度
but it does seem a bit concerning
但还是很担忧
that one of our rangers is sat up in a tree.
我们的一个护林员已经爬到了树上
But the dragons show no interest in the buffalo or the crew
但是科莫多龙看起来对水牛和人都没兴趣
and the frustration continues.
失望在继续
Yet their task seems so simple.
看起来任务相当简单
So all we need
我们只需拍下
isfor him to film him attacking him.
它攻击它的画面
But it looks like he isabout to attack him.
但它看起来准备攻击另一个
Just cut myself, that's not good in dragon country.
不小心割伤了，在龙的地盘可不太妙
I better be careful.
我必须格外小心
Now we've gotta start our walk home, it takes just over an hour
现在我们打算收拾回营，只需一小时
but the thing is, if stuff's happenedand you've got,
但问题是，如果事情发生了
you've managed to film good stuff then it, it's really easy,
你很顺利地拍到了
you just trot on home andfind some dinner
你会快速回去弄点吃的
and find out what the rats have done to your room.
然后在屋子里谈论一番
But it's still really hot at this time of day
但此时正是一天中非常炎热的时候
and so, if you've not filmed a lot
正因如此，如果你没拍到什么好东西
and you've just sat here all day long,
只是在这里傻等一天
thenit's a hell of a long walk home.
回去时一路上肯定会很不爽
They have a lot of long walks home but finally a new dragon appears,
他们已经来回很多趟了，终于，又来了一条龙
something about its attitude seems different.
它的举止看起来不太一样
Maybe we could be onto something but I've now lost that other dragon,
或许会有所斩获，但是我们发现另一条龙不见了
which makes me a bit nervous.
这让我们有些紧张
At first it's wary,
开始只是试探
unwilling to get too close to the buffalo.
不愿太靠近水牛
Big dragons involved here.
较大的龙也来了
That came from absolutely nowhere.
就像忽然冒出来似地
That guy has got some real attitude.
那家伙看起来是认真的
That first bite and the smell of blood set off a chain reaction.
第一口咬下去，鲜血的味道引发连锁反应
All the dragons seem to come to life.
所有的龙都活跃起来
The peaceful watering hole is now a dangerous place to be.
平静的水池现在成了危险的场所
Well, I've definitely got two heads at the moment,
是的，此时我一定是两头想
one as a cameraman saying, "Yes, brilliant!"
就像某个摄影师所说：太帅了
And the other one's thinking, "That poor animal," you know,
另一个则说，可怜的动物
"That's not nice, that's really not nice."
那样不好，真的不好
Quickly, quick,
快点，再快点
quick, quick.
快上呀
My heart's pumping a bit.
我的心跳加速
At least my heart still works. Good Lord, that was a bit hairy.
至少心脏还能运作，天啊，真的有点毛骨悚然
Now the crew must follow the buffalo everyday
现在，摄制组必须每天跟着那头水牛
to finish their filming job.
以便完成整个拍摄
This begins to take a toll on their emotions.
这个则很消耗他们的感情
He knows he's injured, he can't walk properly
它知道自己受伤了，不能正常行走
and he's got these predators just gathering around him,
一些猎食者则在周围
waiting for the opportunity.
等待时机
It's gruesome.
很可怕
Shadowing the buffalo means staying close to the dragons too.
跟着水牛，也意味着与龙共舞
This is mad we've, just, just followed a, the buffalo
我们很疯狂，跟着那头水牛
and, I think, six dragons, I've lost track now,
我想，有六条龙，我跟丢了
I think it's six dragons, down into the riverbed
有六条龙到了河床
and, you know, it's, they're stalking it,
但你知道，它们就躲在附近
we're all a bit nervous,
我们都有些紧张
this is actually quite frightening, I have to say.
这的确很吓人的说
They're so capable and so unafraid of us
它们非常强悍，一点也不怵我们
and they would have no problems at all
它们能毫不费力地
of causing us major, major damage.
对我们造成致命伤害
At the moment I feel about 5 to 10% confident that I'm safe here
那个时候我只有5%-10%的安全把握
but the truth is we just don't know.
但真实情况我们是不知道的
As the days pass,Kevin and Matt
日子一天天过去，Kevin和Matt
can't help butfeel more deeply involved.
免不了更加投入感情
I'm sure they're starting tothink of us as death,
我确信，摄制组开始期盼
you know, the camera team.
出现死亡
Because, although we, you know, we're not influencing it
因为，就算我们一直没有介入
in anyway, really, we're always therewhen the dragon's there
但不管怎么说，我们一直跟着水牛和龙
and, you know,she's sick so we're following her
你知道，它受伤了，我们一直跟着
and you see her looking backat you
它会回头望着你
and I'm sure I feel like death and his scythe's comingin to kill.
我确信已经感受到了死亡的气息
I'm not really that sure how cut out I am for this.
我不知道如何从这个氛围里跳出来
If, if the game is spendingall your time watching an animaldie...
如果你花很长时间观察一只动物如何死去
I don't know about that.
那不知是什么滋味
The dragons seem brutal,
科莫多龙看起来野蛮无情
yet this is the only way they can get large prey.
但这是它们获得大型猎物的唯一手段
For the team, the event has become personal.
对我们来说，这只是它们的私人恩怨
I think as we've got to know himand, you know,
我想我们已经熟悉它了
we've seen him everymorning, we've seen him everyevening
我们每个早晨、每个夜晚都会看见它
and, you know, you build up arelationship with him
和它建立了某种关系
and, and todayI think he, he kind of gave up.
今天，我想，它已经放弃了
The next dayit isall over.
接下来一天，一切都结束了
Now it's over, you sit back and reflect and you sort of feel,
结束了，你坐在一旁，有种感觉
that was just astonishing.
太奇妙了
And it feels so primeval.
如此原始的感觉
It feels we're watching something from a different era.
刚刚目睹了另一个纪元的事情
And they really are the most fantastic things to be with.
这真是最为奇妙的事情
Scary....
可怕
awesome, you know, to look at
看起来很酷，你知道的
you just feel that you are looking at something from Jurassic Park.
你感觉就像在目睹侏罗纪公园里发生的故事